主演：克林特・伊斯特伍德
片名：荒野大镖客
主演：玛丽安・科赫
导演：瑟吉欧・莱昂内
你？又来了！出去！
You? You again! Get out!
按照我说的去做，出去！
Do what I told you. Get out!
继续！跑！我跟你说离我远点了
Go on! Run! I'll teach you to keep away from me!
跑！
Run!
爸爸！
Papa!
你这头蠢猪！
You filthy dog!
你会给我惹麻烦的
You'll settle with me!
我们走
Let's go.
欢迎你，陌生人
Welcome to you, stranger.
我叫胡安・迪欧斯，我是撞钟人
My name is Juan de Dios. I am the bell ringer.
你为什么来这里呢？ 想见洛乔斯？
Why are you here? To see the Rojos?
不，不是洛乔斯 或者可能是巴克斯特？
No, not the Rojos. Is it the Baxters maybe?
甚至也不是巴克斯特
Maybe not even the Baxters.
你想发财，是吗？
You want to get rich, eh?
如果那样想的话，你就来对了
Well, for that you have come to the right place...
如果你想想的话
If you use your head.
因为这里的每个人都很富裕
That's because everybody here has become very rich...
否则就死
or else they are dead.
你想买什么呢？ 枪？酒？
What do you want to buy? Some guns? Liquor?
你不买，你是卖 你卖铅来换黄金
You don't buy. You sell. You sell lead in exchange for gold.
在这你会发财的，要么就是死
You will get rich here, or you'll be killed.
胡安・迪欧斯又撞钟了
Juan de Dios tolls the bell once again.
在离家这么远的地方闲逛不是很聪明的事情
It's not smart to go wandering so far from home.
我想他选错路了
I reckon he picked the wrong trail.
或者就是选错镇了
Or he could have picked the wrong town.
他最大的错，我想就是出生
His big mistake, I think, was getting born.
如果你想找事做，那样看的话…
If you want any work, lookin' like that...
你会死的很难看的
you could try bein' a scarecrow.
噢，不，或者乌鸦很容易就可以把他吓坏
Oh, no, the crows are liable to scare him maybe.
你好
Hello.
你那样是不能发财的
You can't get rich like that.
至少，你只会死的更快
At most, you will only succeed in being killed.
看看我们这里的问题，我们所需要的就是你
With all of the trouble we have, all we needed was you.
- 你在找什么呢？ - 食物和喝的东西
- What are you looking for? - Food and something to drink.
- 水在那里 - 不，不要水
- Water's over there. - No, no water.
吃，喝，然后杀戮
Eating and drinking and killing.
你所能做的就那些，像你们那些人一样
That's all you can do, just like the rest of your kind.
顺便说一下，你要记在账上
By the way, you'll have to mark this up.
我知道，你没有钱
I know. You have no money.
毕竟，你刚刚进这个镇里
After all, you just got into town.
但是如果你不怕杀人的话
But if you don't mind doing a little killing...
找到帮你付钱的人不是很难
You will have no trouble finding someone eager to pay you.
我的轮盘机在转着 那个也是杀人
My roulette wheel. That, too, was murdered.
没有人来这里是玩的
No one ever comes here to play.
我们这里只是葬礼和埋葬
We spend our time here between funerals and burials.
从没有看过这么死寂的镇
Never saw a town as dead as this one.
你不会看到另外一个的
You will never see another like it.
- 这到底怎么了？ - 杀人的事情太多了
- What's wrong with the place? - We've had too many killings.
你看到那些女人了吗？
You have seen the women?
她们都不是女人，她们是寡妇
None of them are women. They're widows.
这个地方都是寡妇
The place is only widows.
在这里，只有杀人才能获得别人的尊敬
Here you can only gain respect by killing other men.
所以再也没有人工作了
So nobody works anymore.
看来有人不同意你的观点
Seems somebody doesn't share your opinion.
是的
Yes.
知道为什么配里皮洛看你吗？
Know why Piripero looked you over?
猜测你
To take your measurements.
他阅历丰富，一眼就可以看出来
He is so experienced. he can do it with a glance.
你会是个顾客
You will be a customer.
不要笑，我不是说笑
Don't laugh. I'm not joking.
我警告你，那些歹徒有天会杀了你的
I want to warn you that those murderers will make a corpse out of you one day.
所以我想让你离开这里
That's why I want you to get out of here.
你不想呆在墓地里吧
You don't want to stay in this cemetery.
快吃完，离开这里
Finish up and get out.
我跟你说过我没钱
I told ya I can't pay ya.
做我的客人…
Be my guest...
离开桑・米吉尔，好吗？
but get out of San Miguel, will you?
这是往哪里的呢？
Where does that lead?
阳台
The balcony.
你为什么上去呢？喂
Why are you going there? Hey!
看看
To have a look.
从高处看的话，总是会发现一些新东西
Things always look different from higher up.
但是上面什么都没有
But nothing's up there.
快点离开这里
Go ahead and get out!
他们是谁呢？
Who are they?
强盗，强盗和走私犯
Bandits. Bandits and smugglers.
他们从德克萨斯来的
They come down from Texas.
他们穿越边境来囤积枪和酒
They cross the frontier to stock up on guns and liquor.
这里的成本比较低
The cost is much less here.
然后他回去把枪和酒卖给印第安人
Then they go back and sell the guns and liquor to the Indians.
每个卖枪和酒的城镇都会是个富裕的城镇
Any town that sells guns and liquor has gotta be a rich one.
不是镇里的人，只是那些卖的人
Not the town, only those who buy and sell...
还有那些头
and the bosses are the ones who clean up.
是吗？应该有人管理这个地方. 每个镇都有头的
Yeah? Somebody has to run the place. Every town has a boss.
那是的，但是如果有两个的话…
That's true, but when there are two around...
那么有一个就是多余的了
then I'd say that there is one too many.
两个头？
Two bosses?
真有趣
Very interesting.
有趣是对的
Interesting is right.
洛乔斯，卖酒的三兄弟
The Rojos boys, three brothers who sell liquor.
那边的是巴克斯特，大军火商
And then there's the Baxters, big gun merchants.
如果我没弄错的话，你已经见过巴克斯特的人了，不是吗？
If I'm not mistaken, you already met Baxter's gang, didn't you?
是的，见过了
Yeah, we met.
但是你很幸运 他们不是一直只对准骡的
But you're lucky. They don't usually limit their fire to the mule.
一个男人离开自己的地方，在这里四处张望
A man leaves his own land and looks around for any reason...
胡安・迪欧斯敲一下钟，然后配里皮洛卖另外一副棺材
Juan de Dios tolls the bell and Piripero sells another coffin.
两个头
Two bosses.
他们招募边境两边所有能战斗的人
They've enlisted all the scum that hangs around both sides of the frontier...
他们用美元付钱
and they pay in dollars.
巴克斯特在那里
The Baxters over there.
洛乔斯在那
The Rojos there.
我就在中间
Me right in the middle.
你想去哪里？
Where you do what?
撞钟人是对的
Crazy bell ringer was right.
在这样的地方可以发财
There's money to be made in a place like this.
如果你说那样想的话，跟你说，不要试
If you're thinking what I suspect, I tell you, don't try it.
他们两个谁比较厉害？
Which one of the two is the stronger?
Which one of them is stronger?
洛乔斯，尤其是雷蒙
Well, the Rojos, especially Ramon.
米吉尔・罗吉先生，我想跟你说话
Don Miguel Rojo, I want to talk to you.
米吉尔先生，我听说你想要人
Don Miguel, I hear you're hiring on men.
我可能很适合
Well, I might just be available.
在你雇佣我之前，我想告诉你
I gotta tell you before you hire me...
我不是很便宜的
I don't work cheap.
准备三副棺材
Get three coffins ready.
再见，朋友
Adios, amigo.
听着，陌生人！你还没想好吗？
Listen, stranger! Didn't you get the idea?
我们不想在镇里看到像你那样的人
We don't like to see bad boys like you in town.
去找你的骡
Go get your mule.
你这样让它跑了吗？
You let him get away from you?
我正想跟你们说这事
That's what I want to talk to you about.
- 它的感受很不好 - 什么？
- He's feeling real bad. - Hmm?
我的骡
My mule.
你们朝它的脚开枪，把它激怒了
He got all riled up when you men fired those shots at his feet.
喂，你在说笑吗？
Hey, are you makin' some kind of joke?
我知道你们这些人只是玩玩
I understand you men were just playin' around.
但是骡…它不明白
But the mule... He just doesn't get it.
当然，如果你们道歉的话
Of course, if you were to all apologize.
你们笑，我觉得并不是很好
I don't think it's nice, you laughin'.
我的骡不喜欢别人笑
My mule don't like people laughin'.
它知道你们在笑它，它会很愤怒的
He gets the crazy idea you're laughin' at him.
现在，如果你们道歉的话，你们准备…
Now, if you apologize, like I know you're going to...
我会让它相信，你们不是有意的
I might convince him that you really didn't mean it.
我都看见了 你杀了他们四个
I saw the whole thing. You killed all four of them.
你会付出代价的 你会被绞死的
You'll pay all right. You'll be strung up.
你是谁？
Who are you?
别开枪
Don't fire a shot.
我叫约翰・巴克斯特，警长
I'm John Baxter, sheriff.
是吗？如果你是警长的话
Yeah? Well, if you're the sheriff,
你最好把这些人埋了
you better get these men underground.
我说错了，四副棺材
My mistake. Four coffins.
我跟你说了我不是很便宜的
I told you I wasn't cheap...
但是我想你会觉得这是值得的
but I think you'll find it's worth your while.
97，98，99，啊
97, 98, 99, 100.
剩下的在你完成后再给
The rest when you're all done.
我什么时候开始？
When do I start?
我不急，至少现在
I'm not in a hurry, at least for the moment.
我会说跟巴克斯特在一起，现在做什么事情都不错
I'd say with four less Baxters, right now is as good a time to start as any.
我听说再过几天有一队骑兵经过这里
In a few days I hear there will be a troop of cavalry passing through here.
我不想让军队的人干扰我们的生意
I wouldn't want the military sticking their long noses into our business.
看来你的消息很灵通
You seem to be well informed.
在这些地方，人的生命经常依靠这些信息
In these parts, a man's life often depends on a mere scrap of information.
这个东西对他们的主人没什么大帮助
This thing couldn't have been very useful to its owner.
我兄弟雷蒙的 他经常用来做目标练习
My brother Ramon did that. He often uses it for target practice.
手里拿着枪，没有人敢挡住他
With a gun in his head, no one stands in his way.
这件装甲是他最喜欢的目标之一
The suit of armor is one of his favorite targets...
特别是没有什么其他东西来射的时候
Naturally when he does not have anything better to shoot.
我对见你的兄弟很有点兴致了
Well, I'll be kind of curious to meet this brother of yours.
这个是奇科，最可靠的人之一
This is Chico, one of the most trusted of my men.
跟着他，他会带你去你的房间
Follow him. He will bring you to your room.
希望你像在家里一样
I would like you to feel at home.
我还没有找到那么好的家，我们走
Well, I never found home that great, but let's go.
她是谁？
Who's that?
她叫玛丽莎 你最好忘了她
Her name's Marisol. You just forget about her.
这是你的房间
This one will be your room.
你给了他100美元
You gave him $100.
我们从来不付那么多钱
We never pay that much.
你能向我解释为什么接受他吗？
Can you explain to me why you have taken him on?
让那个恶心的外国佬呆在这里，还给他100美元？
To have that filthy gringo around the house and to give him $100 besides?
我们从来没给过那么高的价钱
We have never paid anybody so much
你不能把那样的人留在这里，做他想做的事情
You cannot leave someone like that to do what he wants around here.
他什么事情都可以做
He's capable of doing anything.
我想要这里有些秩序
And I want law and order in this place.
如果你想的只是那样的话，那么就更便宜了
If that is all you want, there is a much cheaper way.
杀掉他
Just snuff him out.
谁来呢？你？
And who would be the one? You?
是的，为什么不呢？
Yes, why not?
后面开枪，很容易就解决他了
A shot in his back, then you would have him out of the way in no time at all.
听着，我很容易就可以做到了
Listen, I could do it easily right now.
他不会想到的，我就可以拿回那一百元
He won't be expecting it, and I'd get back the hundred.
你真蠢，伊斯特班！ 即使你是我弟弟
You are stupid, Esteban! Even if you are my brother!
后面开枪，是吗？ 结束了
A bullet in the back, eh? And it is ended!
如果你的手打颤会怎样呢？
And what happens if your hand should tremble slightly?
就他受伤吗？
And he's only hurt?
而且骑兵很快就来到这里了
And with the cavalry arriving in town and that Yankee so quick on the draw.
- 我只是想… - 你什么都不要想
- I was only thinking... - You mustn't think of anything!
让我来想
You let me do the thinking instead.
去看看美国人 看看他需要什么，跟他交个朋友
Go and see the americano. Just ask him if he needs anything and make friends.
你要记住一点
Get one thing clear in that head of yours.
在雷蒙回来之前不要发生任何事情
This is going to be a quiet town until Ramon gets back!
明白吗？别发生什么事情
Is that clear? A quiet town.
我是伊斯特班・罗吉 我哥哥叫我…
I am Esteban Rojo. My brother asked me to...
你在做什么呢？
What are you doing?
走
Moving.
但是你不知道我们所有的人都是住在一起的吗？
But didn't you know all our men live here with us?
是很舒适，但是我觉得你们并不是都很欢迎我
That's all very cozy, but I don't find you men all that appealin'.
而且，你哥哥说现在没什么事需要我做
Besides, your brother said he didn't have any need for me anymore right now.
停！
Halt!
- 军士？ - 什么事，长官？
告诉他们今晚我们在这里休息
Tell the men we'll be spending tonight here in this place.
安排一下，让他们补充一下东西
Arrange it so they can pick up the supplies here.
还有，加强警卫，守卫好马车
Also, double the guard in order to watch the stagecoach there.
是的
Yes, sir.
你觉得那马车里是什么呢？
What do you suppose they're carrying in that coach?
很容易查明
It'd be easy to find out.
走进它，然后看看里面是什么
Get up close to it and take a little look at what's in it.
如果他们向你开枪，那么里面就是金子
If they fire at you, you know it's gold.
不错的主意
Not a bad idea.
看什么呢？
Looking for anything?
你好
Hello.
离开这里，年轻人
Get out of here, Yankee.
你怎么没睡呢？
Why aren't you sleeping?
当你的眼神那样的时候，让我觉得不安
When I see you staring like that, it bothers me.
我还在想那马车里的是什么
I still keep wondering what was in that stagecoach.
肯定是什么他们认为很重要的东西
It's something they seem to think is very important.
我问了那统帅几个问题，差点被抓住了
I asked a few questions of the captain and almost was arrested.
玛丽莎是谁？
Who's Marisol?
你最好睡觉 你需要的
You better get some sleep. You need it.
这太危险了，即使是你
It's much too dangerous, even for you.
我只是问她是谁
All I did is ask who she was.
她是个女人
She is a woman.
雷蒙疯狂的爱上了她
And Ramon's madly in love with her.
现在明白了吧？
Does that make it clear to you?
镇里的每一个人都谈论雷蒙
Everybody in this town talks about Ramon.
真的很想见见他
Kind of curious to meet him.
如果你够聪明的话
If you are smart, you will try to stay
你会尽可能离他远点
clear of Ramon as long as possible.
那里有士兵 他们静静的前进着
There are the soldiers. They are moving on very quietly.
好奇怪
Strange.
他们跑向边境
They're headed for the frontier.
告诉我
Tell me...
你每晚都是这样睡觉的吗？
is that the way you go to bed every night?
别担心，我不会弄脏被单的
Don't worry. I didn't dirty the sheets.
等等，我也去
Wait. I'm coming too.
我想想看看你是怎样惹麻烦上身的
I want to see for myself how you're going to get yourself in trouble.
好的，好的，走
All right. All right. Go ahead.
就像玩牛仔和印第安人一样
It's like playing cowboys and Indians.
- 上尉 - 欢迎，中尉
- Captain. - Welcome, Lieutenant.
这是给你们的金子
There's your gold as promised.
希望你们给我们的枪对我们的军队有相同的用处
I hope the guns you will be giving us will be equally useful to our army.
放心，上尉 我们检查一下
Rest assured, Captain. We'll check them over together.
穿上他们的衣服，快点
Get their clothes on again, and hurry.
把他们放好
Be sure to place them around right.
记得，他们是互相战死的
Remember. They died fighting among themselves.
卢比奥！
Rubio!
那个，就是雷蒙
There. It's Ramon.
这是我的兄弟雷蒙
This is my brother Ramon.
我想我提过他了
I think I mentioned him.
每个人都在说雷蒙
Everybody talks about Ramon.
也有很多人说你，包括我亲爱的兄弟
And many speak of you, too, my dear brother included.
希望他们说的是好事
Well, I hope they say nice things.
你的旅途不错吧？
Did you have a good trip?
很无聊
It was tiring.
在路上的时候太热了
It was terribly hot on the road during the day.
坐马车不是很舒服
And stagecoaches are an uncomfortable way to travel.
我想很快你就会高兴起来了
Well, I'm sure you'll be in great shape in no time.
美国人已经迫不及待了
The americano cannot wait to get into action.
对不起 恐怕要让他伤心了
I am sorry. He's going to be a disappointed man.
怎么呢
How's that?
巴克斯特接受了邀请 他们今晚会来的，米吉尔先生
The Baxters accepted the invitation. They'll come tonight, Don Miguel.
巴克斯特来这里？ 你肯定是疯了
The Baxters coming here? You must be out of your head.
奇科是听我的命令的 我告诉他邀请他们过来
Chico followed my orders. I told him to invite them here.
雷蒙，这是什么意思？
Ramon, what is this?
在旅途之中我发现了很多新东西
I have found out many things when I was traveling...
觉得我们这样彼此争斗，毫无结果
and I have decided that it's very stupid...
是非常愚蠢的
to just keep on shooting at each other and without any results.
你疯了，雷蒙
You've gone out of your mind, Ramon.
不，我很正常，伊斯特班
No, I have come to my senses, Esteban.
相信我
Believe me.
Trust me.
生活很宝贵
Life can be so precious.
浪费每一分钟都是愚蠢的，不是吗？
It's foolish to risk losing it every minute, no?
这个镇子的空间很大，足够所有的人生活
There's plenty of space for everybody in this town.
即使巴克斯特也是，是吗？
Even Baxters, hmm?
因为这样…
For this reason...
我决定把自己的枪挂到墙上
I've decided to hang my gun up on the wall.
我觉得雷蒙说得对
I think that Ramon has the right idea.
我，也厌倦了这些杀戮 必须停下来
I, too, am getting tired of these killings. They must stop.
这，真的很让人感动
This is all very, very touching.
你是说你不赞赏和平？
You mean you don't admire peace?
这对于你来说可能是很难理解的事情
It's not real easy to like something you know nothing about.
呆在桑・米吉尔，你会学会很多事情的
Stay in San Miguel and you may just profit from the experience.
不，谢谢，我会走的
No, thanks. I'll be movin' on.
钱在这，米吉尔先生
Here's your money, Don Miguel.
我只是用了一点
I only used a small amount of it.
除非我觉得我赚到了，要不然我不会拿的
I don't like to take money unless I feel I've earned it.
现在，你为什么这么匆忙呢？ 你应该呆在这里
Now, why are you so hasty? You should stay here.
今晚你可以和我们一起吃晚饭
You might enjoy dining with us tonight.
因为我，巴克斯特有四个人死了
The Baxters have four men in the cemetery on account of me.
我想他们不会很希望看到我在场的
I don't think they'd appreciate my presence.
我不喜欢那个美国人，他太聪明了
I don't like that americano. He's too smart to be just a hired fighter.
- 开枪的时候没人可以比的上他 - 我看得出来
- At shooting a gun no one can touch him. - I can see that.
长着那样脸的人拿枪，你可以猜测到两件事情
When someone with that face works with his gun, you may count on two things.
他开枪很快，但是他也很聪明
He's fast on the trigger, but he's also intelligent.
他对于你们来说太危险了，兄弟们
That makes him too dangerous for you, I think, my brothers.
既然他走了，你能向我们解释一下…
Now that he's gone, will you please explain that silly nonsense...
把枪搁在墙上，和巴克斯特和好的那些事情吗？
about hanging up your gun and making up with the Baxters?
你自己想不到吗？
Is it possible that you'll never be able to reach any conclusions on your own?
你们觉得我们政府和美国人不会发现尸体
Don't you think our government and the americanos will find those bodies...
然后开始调查吗？
and then start an investigation?
他们会调查的，好的…
They'll investigate, all right...
我们安静，容忍一会
and we'll be quiet and peacefully abide our time.
我们对于里奥・布拉沃的大屠杀一无所知，是吗？
We know nothing about the massacre at the Rio Bravo, eh?
我把尸体安排成…
I arranged for the bodies to be lying...
他们是对战死的
as if both companies killed each other.
你们觉得他们相信吗？
But do you think they'll believe it?
是的，我想是的
Yes, I think so.
因为如果他们找不到一些作案的团体…
Because if they don't find some guilty party...
他们只能取消调查
It would be a pretty good reason to call off the investigation.
是的，那么巴克斯特怎么办呢？
Yes, but what about the Baxters?
巴克斯特？
The Baxters?
他们只是想着和平共处
They want nothing more than to live in peace.
我们就暂时满足他们的想法
We'll let them have their own way for a while.
别理巴克斯特
Forget about the Baxters.
调查结束之后我们再好好对付他们
We'll take care of them later when the investigation finishes.
你的想法不错
That was a fine idea that you had.
有是了吗？
What was it again?
啊，是的，是的
Ah, yes, yes, yes.
巴克斯特在这边，洛乔斯在那边
The Baxters are on one side. The Rojos on the other.
你就在中间
And you'd be in the middle.
唯一的问题就是他们联合起来了
The only problem is that they've joined up.
现在你做不了什么了
Now you are without a job,
你没有钱付你的帐了
and you don't have money to pay me what you owe me.
你只能做一件事情 赶紧离开这里
There is only one thing for you to do. Leave here immediately.
我会忘记你欠我的
I will forget about what you owe me.
你离开桑・米吉尔，以后再也不要回来了
You leave San Miguel and never come back for the rest of your days.
哦，乔，我已经按照你说的修好了马车
Eh, Joe, I have prepared the wagon the way you asked me to.
后面还有两幅空棺材
It's sitting out in the back here with two empty coffins.
你想做什么呢？
What are you up to?
你想换职业了吗？
Are you changing your profession?
如果你想谋生的话，你可以更好的
If you want to go on living, you'd better.
我觉得，你会是个很好的护柩人
In my opinion, you'll make a fine pallbearer.
关了这里，跟我一起走，好吗？
Close this place and come with me, huh?
哦，关了，是吗？好了 我们去哪里呢？
Oh, close up, huh? It's done. Where are we going?
我想知道我们去哪里，这是秘密吗？
I'd like to know where we are going, or is it a secret?
到河下面去 找一些下面的尸体
Down by the river. Have a look at some corpses down there.
洛乔斯说吃晚饭，我们必须去
The Rojos say come to dinner and we must go.
布特一点也不喜欢那个
But I don't like it at all...
即使他们已经保证我们所要求的所有东西
even if they've granted all the guarantees we've demanded.
我们一起去，但是什么都不要碰
We'll go along with it, but don't touch anything.
你们不能吃，不能喝
You mustn't eat. You mustn't drink.
你们要注意一切东西，保持警惕
You just keep your eyes open and keep your wits about you.
你确定没有人看着我们？
Are you sure that nobody has seen us?
只有一两个鬼
Only a ghost or two.
不要开这样的玩笑
Don't joke about things like this.
鬼还是呆在他们的地方好
Ghosts are better left where they are.
看起来这个地方好像很适合你
You look as though this place suits you very well.
如果你再这样的话，你很快就会永远的呆在这里
If you go on like this, you will soon be here permanently.
我不明白
I do not understand.
为什么所有河流下面的尸体
Why is it with all those bodies down
你只埋其中的两具？
by the river we are just burying these two?
不是的，我们不埋
We're not. We're not gonna bury them.
不埋是什么意思呢？
What do you mean we're not burying them?
是的，我们不埋他们
That's right. We're not gonna bury them.
如果我们不埋的话，用他们做什么呢？
If we are not going to bury them, what will we use them for?
我们为什么要费力做这样的事情呢？
Why are we taking the trouble to do this?
死人有时很有用
The dead can be very useful sometimes.
他们可以帮助我们
They've helped me out of tough spots more than once.
首先他们不会说话
First, they don't talk.
其次，如果弄好的话，他们就像生的一样
Second, they can be made to look alive if I manage it right.
还有…
And, third...
如果你向他们开枪的话，别担心
Well, third, if you shot them, there's no worry,
因为他们已经死了
'cause they're dead already.
明白吗？
Understand?
我一点也不明白，我要走了
It doesn't make a bit of sense to me, and I'm getting out.
我活着，我还想活下去，明白吗？
I'm alive, and I want to remain with the living, understand?
当我死了，我就一直死着
And when I'm dead, I'll want to remain with the dead.
活着的人让我活起来我会不开心的
I would be unhappy if somebody living forces me to remain with the living.
希望我说的很清楚
I hope that's clear.
还有，我不喜欢你把他们放在这里的想法
And, also, I don't like the idea that you've placed those bodies there!
埋在那里的人只是那些得肺炎而死的人
The man buried there is the only one who died of pneumonia in this cursed town!
放松点，好吗？
Take it easy, will ya?
这两个我们的朋友会让我可以给你付钱
These two friends of ours here are gonna make me pay your bill.
走吧
Get up there!
他们开战的唯一理由只能是
The only reason they could have to start a war with us...
把你从我身边绑架走了
would be to kidnap you from your husband's side.
他太豪爽了，这个罗吉
He's gallant, this Rojo.
我觉得不能那样恭维他
I really didn't think him capable of compliments.
他不是 他所说的都是假的，就像他的提议
And he's not. All that he says is false, like his proposals.
你们这些女人！如果事情不复杂的时候，你们就怀疑了
You women! If things aren't complicated for you, you become suspicious.
是的，因为对于我来说，事情不是很好
Yes, because to me, it just didn't seem right.
太顺利了 我不相信他们
It went too smoothly. I don't trust them.
你想证明我是错的，不是吗？
You'd like to prove me wrong, wouldn't you?
一直都是这样的
Always the same thing.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
别担心 我不会伤害你的
Don't worry. I'm not gonna hurt ya.
我只是想让你知道
I just want you to know why the
为什么洛乔斯这么急着和解
Rojos want to make peace all of a sudden.
有一群士兵拉着满车的黄金
There was once a wagon load of gold that the soldiers
去边界那
were taking to the border.
约翰，快点上来
John, come up here quickly.
对不起，但是当丈夫发现一个男人在自己妻子的卧室里
Sorry, but when a husband finds a man in his wife's bedroom...
你绝对不会知道他的反应会是怎样的
you're never sure how he's gonna react.
- 给他500美元 - 为什么？
- Give him $500. - How's that?
给他钱
Give the money to him.
他有个有趣的故事 听他说
He has an interesting story. Listen to him.
那是很好的故事 你不会不明白的
That's the right idea. You didn't misunderstand.
只有合适我的时候我才会误解
I get the wrong idea only when it suits me.
- 什么呢？ - 护送金子的士兵
- What is it? - The soldiers escorting the gold!
两个逃走了 他们躲在墓地里
Two of those soldiers got away. They are hiding out in the cemetery.
巴克斯特 他们想抓住他们
The Baxters. They're about to capture them.
叫他们集合
Get the men!
你的消息很灵通，是吗？
You are well informed, eh?
人的生命通常就靠信息
A man's life in these parts often depends on a mere scrap of information.
你兄弟自己说的
Your brother's own words.
告诉我，你为什么这样帮我们？
Tell me. Why are you doing this for us?
500美元
$500.
抓住这两个对雷蒙不利的士兵…
With these two soldiers as witnesses against Ramon...
政府会消灭洛乔斯，还有他们所有的人
the government will be able to rid the town of the Rojos and their whole band.
那时桑・米吉尔只有一个头
Then San Miguel will have just one boss.
快点！
Hurry!
我们走
Let's go!
跟我们一起去吗？
Coming with us?
当一个男人口袋里有钱的时候
When a man's got money in his pocket,
他开始欣赏和平
he begins to appreciate peace.
快点！
Come on!
我们把马放在这里
Let's leave the horses here.
谁在那？出来
Who's there? Come out!
你觉得怎样呢？
What do you think?
不知道
I don't know.
我不喜欢这样
There's something about it I don't like.
太安静了，不像受伤 像假人一样
Too still to be wounded. More like dummies.
当然，洛乔斯很感兴趣的家人
Sure, dummies that are very interesting to the Rojos.
最好藏起来，快点
Better hide. Hurry.
我们应该怎样做？
What'll we do?
让两个人绕到旁边
Take two men and circle around to the side.
和他们对战，然后我就可以把那两个人弄过来了
Try to keep them busy long enough for me to get those two down there.
继续，继续，快点
Go on. Go on. Quickly.
掩护 我去看看他们两个
Keep me covered. I am going to take care of those two.
听着，巴克斯特！ 现在，如果你想的话，你可以带他们走了
Listen, Baxter! You can have them now if you like!
因为死人是不会说话的
Since dead men can't talk!
看起来他们不喜欢我这个玩笑
It seems they didn't like my joke.
待会我们让他们回去吧
We'll let them go home in a little while.
我们把这个小子作为我们的客人…
We will keep this bad boy as our guest...
直到巴克斯特离开桑・米吉尔奔向边境
only until Baxter leaves San Miguel and heads for the frontier.
把他放到地下室去
Put him in the cellar.
做的不错
Good work!
用安东尼奥作我们的人质，巴克斯特只好让步了
With Antonio as our prisoner, the Baxters have to give in to us.
现在我们可以要求任何东西了
Now we can make any kind of demand.
发生什么事了？ 说话，可以吗？
What has happened? Talk, will you?
我不知道，但是有人向我开枪
I don't know, but somebody shot at me.
你在哪，玛丽莎？
Where are you, Marisol?
很奇怪，你怎么老是在合适的时间出现呢？
It's strange how you always manage to be in the right place at the right time.
没什么严重的 头疼会过去
It's nothing serious. A headache that will pass.
她会睡着的
She'll sleep.
盯着她，她不能离开那个房间 听到了吗？
Keep your eyes open. She's not to move from that room. You hear?
我不会说我是怎样带她来这里的
I wouldn't mention anything about me bringing her here.
我不想让洛乔斯因为我是你们的人
I wouldn't want the Rojos to think I was on your side.
别担心
Don't worry.
我是个富裕的女人，舍得花钱买值得买的人
I'm a woman who's rich enough to appreciate the men my money can buy.
我已经跟洛乔斯说了
I've been to talk to the Rojos.
他们愿意用安东尼奥换玛丽莎
They'll give back Antonio in exchange for Marisol.
上午的时候开始
It'll take place in the morning.
你很快就会有钱了
Very soon you are going to be rich.
是的，那不会让我伤心的
Yeah, and that's not gonna break my heart.
她在哪？ 你说我可以看到她的
Where is she? You said I'd be able to see her!
她在哪？
Where is she?
我想看她
I wanna see her!
- 回这来，杰西，过来 - 我想看
- Come back here, Jesus. Come here. - I wanna see!
我想看她，我想看她
I want to see her! I want to see her!
我为什么不能看她呢？ 我想看她
Why can't I look at her? I want to see her!
去，去他那，玛丽莎
Go. Go to him, Marisol.
妈妈
Mama!
- 妈妈 - 杰西！
- Mama! - Jesus!
朱里奥！
Julio!
对付朱里奥
Get Julio.
你被警告离开城镇
You were warned to get out of town.
现在我要你一次付清
Now I'm gonna make you pay once and for all.
别动他
Let him be!
你最好走 雷蒙在等着
You better get goin'. Ramon's waitin'.
还有，你，赶快带那个孩子回去
And, you, get that kid home where he belongs.
猪，那个雷蒙
A pig, that Ramon.
雷蒙对他们做了什么呢？
What's Ramon got to do with them?
没有人告诉你，是吗？
You weren't told, eh?
在世界的这个地方，这个故事很久了
In this part of the world, the story is very old.
一个快乐的小家庭，然后麻烦出现了
A happy little family until trouble comes along.
麻烦的名字叫雷蒙
And trouble has the name of Ramon.
说丈夫打牌的时候作弊了，这当然不是真的…
Claiming the husband cheated at cards, which wasn't true...
他把他的妻子抓来做人质
He gets the wife to live with him as hostage.
丈夫呢？
And the husband?
他？他什么都做不了
Him? There's nothing for him to do.
洛乔斯威胁说要杀了他的儿子杰西…
The Rojos threatened to kill his little boy Jesus...
他必须接受这些
and he was forced to accept things.
那个雷蒙很聪明
That Ramon is smart.
你去哪里呢？
Where are you going?
到洛乔斯找事做
To the Rojos to look for a job.
我很开心，美国人和我们在一起
I am glad we have the americano with us.
最好的事情都有可能发生在我们身上…
It's the best thing that could have happened to us, you know...
因为如果政府不进行调查的话
'cause if either government starts an inquiry...
我们需要招收大量的人
We'll need every man we can get.
我想你们应该知道现在和巴克斯特将会有场大战了…
I guess you know to be at war with the Baxters now...
这比坐在一大箱炸药上还糟糕
is worse than sitting on a big case of dynamite.
- 我们应该把这些放哪里呢？ - 放那
- Where should we put this? - Put it over there.
来，大家，喝！
Come on, everybody! Drink up!
好枪法，真的很好的枪法
Good shooting. Very good shooting.
当你想杀人的时候，最好就是射他的心脏
When you want to kill a man, you must shoot for his heart.
温切斯特是最好的武器
And the Winchester is the best weapon.
那很不错，但是我还是坚持用我的a.45
That's very nice, but I'll stick with my a.45.
当带a.45的人遇到用来复枪的人…
When a man with a.45 meets a man with a rifle...
拿着手枪的人会死
The man with the pistol will be a dead man.
那是一句古老的墨西哥谚语，那是真的
That's an old Mexican proverb, and it's true.
你相信吗？
You believe that?
来五个人送玛丽莎回小屋
Take five men and escort Marisol to the small house.
一直待到我回去
Stay there till I return.
- 一切都准备好了 - 不要担心
- Everything's prepared. - Do not be worried.
明天我会回来的
I will return tomorrow.
所有的马车都准备好了 我们可以走了
All the wagons are ready. We can leave.
大家，我不在的时候玩的尽兴
Everyone, enjoy yourselves during my absence.
你们听到雷蒙说的话了 我们要玩的尽兴
You heard Ramon. Let's have a good time.
- 他有一吨重 - 是的
- He weighs over a ton. - Of course...
他喝得太多了
with all he poured into himself.
你不是跟我说谁都不能见妈妈的吗？
Did you not tell me no one could go see Mama?
是的
That's right.
为什么那个人可以看她而我不能呢？
Then why does that man see her when I cannot?
- 我要妈妈 - 不要站在门那里
- I want Mama. - Go away from the door.
安静点！我们不能让别人看到我们
Quiet! We cannot show ourselves.
你必须记住这点 你必须离远点
You must remember that. You must stay away.
好啊
Hello.
有人在小房子那里开枪
There's somebody shooting up at the small house.
赶快上马 快点，我们走
Saddle the horses immediately! Come on. Let's go!
小心
Look out!
给！现在，拿着这些钱
Here you are. Now, take this money.
够你们过一段日子了 现在，穿过边境
It's enough to live on for a while. Now, get across the border.
离桑・米吉尔尽可能的远
Get as much distance between yourselves and San Miguel as possible.
我们要怎样多谢你呢？
How may we thank you for what you are doing?
不要了 在洛乔斯来到之前赶快离开这里
Don't try. Just get goin' before the Rojos get here.
你为什么这样帮我们呢？
Why do you do this for us?
为什么？ 因为我知道有人曾经喜欢过你
Why? 'Cause I knew someone like you once.
那里没有帮助 现在，快走
There was no one there to help. Now, get movin'.
离开这里
Get movin'.
Get out of here!
怎么了，奇科？
What do you see, Chico?
他们都死了 他们屠杀了他们
They're all dead. They massacred them.
他们绑架了玛丽莎！ 看来像是巴克斯特做的
- They kidnapped Marisol! - Looks like the work of the Baxters.
快点，在他们攻击我们之前赶快回去
Quick, let's get back before they attack our house and the town.
奇科，把武器分下去
Chico, give out the ammunition.
伊斯特班，让你的人防守房子 警惕点
Esteban, spread your men around the house. Keep your eyes open.
米吉尔、帕克、文森特、马丁，到后面去
Miguel, Paco, Vincente, Martin, behind the house.
阿瓦罗，跟我来 要警惕
Alvaro, come with me. Stay alert.
看他们杀了小房子的人，他们肯定有很多人
The way they killed the men in the small house, there must be a lot of them.
这是很热的晚上
It's a warm evening.
我们有辆马车坏了，所以我们必须回来找人帮助
One of our wagons lost a wheel, so we had to turn back here to get help.
有人告诉我…
One of the men tells me...
巴克斯特袭击了小房子
the Baxters attacked the small house.
你知道吗？
Do you know about it?
告诉我你所知道的
Tell me what you know.
你把玛丽莎藏哪了？
Where did you hide Marisol?
你很渴了 想喝点吗？
You are thirsty. You want to drink?
不，不，现在喝还太早了
No, no, it is too soon to drink.
把他带过来
Bring him over here!
你就像一个顽固的白痴一样
You're behaving like a stubborn idiot.
告诉我们玛丽莎在哪
Tell us where Marisol is...
事情就结束了
and it will all be ended!
一个星期之后，你就复原了 你可以随便去哪里
In a week, you'll be back in shape. You can go wherever you want.
今天够了
That's enough for today.
很快，他会说出来的 只是时间的问题
Sooner or later, he'll talk. It's just a matter of time.
小心别让他跑了或者死了
Watch out he doesn't escape or die otherwise.
等到他肯说出来 这样，他几乎就没什么感觉了
And wait till he comes to. This way, he hardly feels anything.
我已经想打牌想了三天了
I've had a poker hand waiting three days.
现在我要守在这里！ 当我看着这个美国白痴的时候我不能打牌
Now I'm stuck here! I can't get to it while I'm guarding this americano idiot!
你会觉得这比打牌要有趣的多
I think you will find this more amusing than cards.
所有的命令都不要他死…
All orders are to be sure he does not die...
但是也要让他后悔出生
and also make sure he regrets the day he was born.
那个外国佬睡着了
The gringo is asleep, I imagine.
是的 我会很高兴叫醒他的
That's all right. I'll enjoy waking him up.
- 伊斯特班，那是什么声音？ - 我不知道
- Esteban, what was that noise? - I do not know.
我听到了一声大叫，然后是撞击声
I heard a yell, and then a crash.
躲起来是没用的
It's useless to hide.
你快完了
You're finished playing the smart boy.
去看看阁楼那
Go up and look in the loft.
然后看看桶后面
And take a look behind the barrels!
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here!
快点！快点！
Hurry! Quick!
快弄水来！ 喂，你们，跟我走
Hurry with that water! Hey, you, come with me!
包围城镇！ 封锁所有出去的街道
Surround the town! Block all the streets leading out!
给我找到他
Find him for me!
- 伊斯特班，搜索整个城镇 - 跟我走
- Esteban, search the whole town. - Follow me!
给我找回他来 不管什么代价
Get him back right now! You've got to at any cost!
看看马厩，所有的畜栏，所有的商店
Look in the stables, in every corral, in the stores!
还有教堂
Look for him in the church!
去那！ 每一寸都要搜到
Go in there! Search every inch of it!
搜索所有的地方！ 卢比奥，那里
Search everywhere! Rubio, in here!
如果有人藏他的话，把他们的房子烧了…
If somebody is hiding him, burn their house down...
像狗一样把他们杀了
and kill them like dogs!
你，上那
You, up here!
在巴克斯特附近看看，但是我要他是活的
Look for him near the Baxters, but I want him alive!
活的
Alive!
卢比奥，酒店
Rubio, in the bar.
他说他什么都知道 他想表现的聪明
He says he knows nothing. He's trying to be smart.
带到我这里来
Bring him here to me.
- 我在说实话 - 你什么都不知道，是吗？
- I'm telling the truth. - Well, you know nothing, huh?
你照顾他
You take care of him.
你把他藏哪里了？
Where have you hidden him?
我没有藏起他
I didn't hide him.
你是那个卑劣的美国人的朋友
You're the right friend for that filthy americano.
你也会被同样解决的
You'll end up the same way.
我们找遍了所有的地方
We looked everywhere.
地下室，阁楼，房顶
In his cellar, in the attic, on the roof.
没有什么踪迹
There is no trace.
后面的房间里也没什么人
I couldn't find anybody in the back room.
我想他肯定是求助巴克斯特了
I'm certain he has taken refuge with the Baxters.
那个美国人不蠢 他是那是最好的地方
The americano isn't stupid. He knows that's the best place to hide.
巴克斯特，是吗？
The Baxters, eh?
最好去抓住他
Then better go and get him.
这是做他朋友的惩罚
And that's for being his friend.
该死的
Curse them.
- 过来 - 我看不到人
- Come here. - I can't see anybody.
过来
Come here.
你在里面什么呢？
What are you doing in there?
别介意 帮我出来
Never mind. Get me out of here.
但是你还没有死
But you're not dead yet.
如果你不帮我出去的话，我会的，快点
I will be if you don't get me out of here, quick.
盖上盖子
Get that lid down.
有人还活着
I see some signs of life.
我们准备好，有人很快就出来了
Let's be ready when they decide to come out.
不要开枪！我们投降
Don't shoot! We surrender!
住手！别开枪！我们出来！
Stop! Don't shoot! We're coming out!
- 我投降！别开枪！ - 别开枪！
- I surrender! Hold back your fire! - Don't shoot!
我们投降
We surrender!
住手
Stop.
我想看看这个
I wanna take a look at this.
雷蒙，别开枪！ 我们就出来
Ramon, don't shoot! We're coming out!
我们投降
We surrender!
听着，你赢了 够了
Listen, you've won. It's enough!
我会离开这里的 你要我怎样做都行
I'll get out of town! I'll do whatever you like!
- 你保证吗？ - 我发誓
- You promise that? - I swear it!
你不会撒谎吧？
You won't try a trick of any kind?
不！绝对不会的
None! No, no tricks!
我说过了，我保证 我们会离开的
I said before, I give you my word. We'll leave!
你确定吗？ 你最好先征得你老婆的同意
Are you sure? You had better ask permission of your wife.
可能她不会太高兴
Maybe she won't be too happy!
凶手
Murderers.
他们没有枪
They had no guns.
凶手！ 你们下地狱去吧
Murderers! I hope you rot in hell!
愿你和你的兄弟流血死去！ 你们会受到诅咒的
May you and your brothers die spitting blood! Curse you for this!
凶手！
Murderers!
我们走！ 总之节目已经结束了
Let's go. The show's over anyway.
再找找他 找遍每一车尸体
Keep looking for him. Search among those bodies.
那个美国人肯定在
The filthy americano has to be somewhere!
西尔瓦尼托在哪呢？
Where's Silvanito?
今天有什么新闻？
Any news today?
我必须告诉你坏消息
I have to tell you some news that's pretty bad.
- 我必须告诉你这些，但是… - 西尔瓦尼托在哪呢？
- I hate to tell you this, but... - Where is Silvanito?
今天早上他被雷蒙的人抓住了
He was captured this morning by those men of Ramon's.
他们在镇外面抓住他的 他正往这边走
They grabbed him outside the village. He was on his way to this mine.
他早就有预感了 现在雷蒙抓住他了
He was bringing in some provisions. Ramon's got him now.
他被折磨，但是他不会说出来的
He's being tortured, but he won't talk.
我很了解他 他是顽强的人
I know him well. He's a stubborn man.
不管他们怎么做，他一句话都不会说的，即使会没命
No matter what they do, he won't say a word, even if it means his life.
听我说，他们绝对强迫不了他的
Listen to me. They'll never be able to force him.
现在，愚蠢的家伙，松开你的舌头
Now, fool, loosen up your tongue.
你最好回你的店里
You better get back to your shop, old man.
- 你会有生意了 - 啊，太好了
- You're liable to have some business. - Ah, very good!
我就想听到这些
That's what I wanted to hear.
我给你带来一些小礼物
And I have a little surprise for you that I brought along.
我知道你很需要它！
I know how much you'll need it.
我花了很大的劲才弄到手的
It was very hard to get my hands on.
我第一次用自己的脑子 没有人可以忍受两桶酒的诱惑
I got it by first using my head. No one can resist two barrels of wine.
这样对吗 然后我想…
Isn't that right? Then I thought that...
你可能需要那把枪，我买了另外一个礼物
well, you might need that pistol, and I brought another present.
是炸药 我从洛乔斯那里偷来的
It's dynamite. I stole it from the Rojos.
我想现在是你点燃导火线
And now it seems to me the moment's come for you to light the fuse...
送回给他们的时候了
and send it back to them.
光线还很强烈
Still lots of light.
现在睡觉还太早了
Too early to be asleep yet.
卢比奥，来
Rubio, here.
我不想弄坏了来复枪 我还没找到像这把这么好的
I shouldn't like to ruin the rifle. I could never find another like this.
听着，我们现在试试这个
Listen, let's try it with this one now.
外国佬！
Gringo!
听说你想见我
Heard you wanted to see me.
美国佬已经死了
The americano's dead.
放下他
Let the old man down.
怎么了，雷蒙？
What's wrong, Ramon?
怎么没打到呢？
You losing your touch?
你在害怕吗，雷蒙？
Are you afraid, Ramon?
“杀人的话，最好向心脏开枪”
"You shoot to kill, you better hit the heart."
你自己说的
Your own words.
心脏
The heart.
不要忘记了心脏
Don't forget the heart.
朝心脏开枪，要不然你阻止不了我的
Aim for the heart or you'll never stop me.
当带着a.45的人遇到带着来复的人…
When a man with a.45 meets a man with a rifle...
你说那个拿着手枪的人死
You said the man with the pistol's a dead man.
我们看看是不是真的
Let's see if that's true.
动手啊，上弹开枪
Go ahead, load up and shoot.
喂，听着，乔
Hey, listen, Joe.
听着，我…
Listen, l-l...
看到黄金回来了，你们的政府会很开心的
Well, guess your government will be glad to see that gold back.
还有你，你不想再呆下来，是吗？
And you, you don't want to be here when they get it, eh?
你是说墨西哥政府在一边
You mean the Mexican government on one side...
可能美国政府在另外一边？
and maybe the Americans on the other side?
我，就在中间？
Me, right smack in the middle?
嗯 太危险了
Mm-mmm. Too dangerous.
再见
So long.
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer698
剧终，谢谢观赏
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer